Kamil Salakhiev: Each other one.
Csaba: Hey, hey.
Csaba: I'm still in a call, but… Well, let's hear them.
Csaba: Yeah, just…
Kamil Salakhiev: another call.
Csaba: No, not a valid call. I just missed.
Csaba: Recalling a call center.
Csaba: So he'll be here soon.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, let's wait maybe another minute or two for people to join.
Kamil Salakhiev: Hey, Hayden.
Kamil Salakhiev: Keeping, pinging the people.
Kamil Salakhiev: Hey,
Aarsh Shah: Is Sukun gonna join today?
Kamil Salakhiev: I just pinged him. Yeah, he should join.
Kamil Salakhiev: You know, I asked him… Yeah, I asked him, like.
Kamil Salakhiev: Maybe, what, an hour ago? Yeah, he said…
Kamil Salakhiev: He wanted to join and re-talk about this… Worko.
Kamil Salakhiev: Anyways, I think, yeah, we can just get started, and then, yeah, people join.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, yeah, today… yeah, let's do client updates.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, when Sukun joins, yeah, you will briefly describe this Waggle idea, I think we will discuss it more, maybe, in future meetings.
Kamil Salakhiev: When, yeah, Joa and others, they all also join.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, then…
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, this is not in the agenda, but yeah, if time permits, I can briefly maybe touch on some updates on this blobs idea.
Kamil Salakhiev: Anyways, yeah, let's get started, with client updates.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, Daniel, maybe start with prison? Oh, sorry, with Lighthouse.
Daniel Knopik: I can… I can also, start with Prysm.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, yeah, sounds good. We should do this topic someday.
Daniel Knopik: Okay, okay, from Lighthouse side, we are now in the final review phase for…
Daniel Knopik: partial messages, partial data columns in Gloas. I hope it's merged, like, tomorrow, or the day after, so that's good. And, we also…
Daniel Knopik: have… prepared… The necessary changes for…
Daniel Knopik: sparse blob pool in definite 8, so FCU V4 adjustments and Get blobs V4 should be in those branches.
Daniel Knopik: And also, hopefully, soon, in Unstable.
Daniel Knopik: Yeah, I think that's pretty much it from our side.
Kamil Salakhiev: good things.
Kamil Salakhiev: Aarsh? Any prismatics?
Aarsh Shah: Sure, sure. So yeah, we're very close to…
Aarsh Shah: Merging the gloss partial columns over to the Glamsterdam DevNet 7 branch, and then…
Aarsh Shah: you know, we can start interrupt testing on the Gloas DevNet with Lighthouse. I did the interrupt testing on Kurtosis, and it looks green, which is great.
Aarsh Shah: I also had a call with Sukun… yeah, and, yeah, my next, target now is, to land the Get blobs V4.
Aarsh Shah: and fork choice updated V4 work that, you know, Bosul had raised a PR for.
Aarsh Shah: But I'm now gonna rebase all of that on the Glamsterdam DevNet 7 branch, because there's a lot that we need to add there for it to work seamlessly with partial columns.
Aarsh Shah: So that's, my… yeah, so Bosul will let you know when it's, you know, I've taken it to completion, tested it, etc, and I think we'll release it along with Gloas. No, actually, no, we can get it and develop before that. I'll keep you updated.
Aarsh Shah: Yeah, and one more… yeah, I had a nice call with Sukun on Friday about Waggle.
Aarsh Shah: Personally, from Prysm, we are very excited about,
Aarsh Shah: the idea of Waggle, you know, basically…
Aarsh Shah: a gossip sub-library built specifically for Ethereum.
Aarsh Shah: That has first-class support for partial messages, EC-broadcast, and…
Aarsh Shah: doesn't have all the heavy control messages that gossip-sub has. You know, basically less code is better, and something that is more ETH-aware in terms of PubSub, that would really… that is a pretty good idea.
Aarsh Shah: So we were coming around to it, so I had a call with Sukun that, you know, we are very interested in working closely on the Go implementation to land it. Like, you know, we can pair up with Sukun and join teams and land the…
Aarsh Shah: Go implementation, and of course, the spec.
Aarsh Shah: So yeah, when I'll… whenever he's up next, we'll… we'll… just… I'm just interested in understanding the…
Aarsh Shah: Consensus mechanism around it. Like, are all client teams on board? We can do it without a hard fork, for sure.
Aarsh Shah: Just be a bit trickier, because…
Aarsh Shah: Either the app layer speaks both Waggle and the old goal of P2PubSub.
Aarsh Shah: or we make Waggle inside, go B2BP, PubSub, and then…
Aarsh Shah: later get rid of everything we don't need, so it becomes Waggle.
Aarsh Shah: Only?
Aarsh Shah: Yeah, so there is a way to do it with a hard fork, without a hard fork.
Aarsh Shah: just wanted to… whenever we all meet next, along with Sukun, I think we should…
Aarsh Shah: Kind of get some consensus on how many teams are interested in shipping it, what the timeline's roughly.
Aarsh Shah: look like? By when do you think we think we can have a spec, ready?
Aarsh Shah: You know,
Aarsh Shah: So yeah, yeah, let's do it in the next call, then. And daniel, I had a… I found a bug when doing Gloas testing for partial columns.
Aarsh Shah: I suspect you might have a similar bug in Lighthouse. Basically, if…
Aarsh Shah: the Get blobs v3 call and the has blobs call both return nothing.
Aarsh Shah: Like, basically, there's not a single… blob in your mempool.
Aarsh Shah: In that case, you should still push out
Aarsh Shah: Like, you know, a request bitmap of all ones, and an included bitmap of all zeros.
Aarsh Shah: To the peers, so they can send you all the columns.
Aarsh Shah: That you're looking for, if that makes sense.
Daniel Knopik: I thought this is handled properly, but I'll check it.
Aarsh Shah: Take a look.
Daniel Knopik: Yeah, because…
Aarsh Shah: I had missed it, and it, it was sometimes causing problems when Get blobs V3 and HES blobs both returned empty.
Aarsh Shah: Just to.
Daniel Knopik: Yeah, actually, Has blobs is not in the codebase right now. It's…
Daniel Knopik: Yeah, not, not actively utilized, so,
Daniel Knopik: Let's see. But… but I'll check, I'll check.
Aarsh Shah: Okay, sure.
Csaba: What is the issue, Del?
Csaba: It is that you have to push out the message anyway, or…
Aarsh Shah: Yeah, yeah, like, basically, if… Even if you have nothing, even if you have zero blobs.
Aarsh Shah: In your mempool, so the EL Get blobs call returns nothing.
Aarsh Shah: You should still push out a request.
Aarsh Shah: saying, I want all the blobs because I have nothing. Like, basically, I want all the columns because I want… I have nothing.
Csaba: Yeah, so what's the semantics that,
Csaba: should the other side know that you need all, or is it getting it from your signaling? Because if it's getting it from your signaling, then…
Csaba: then that's the expected thing, right? You have to signal that you need.
Aarsh Shah: Yeah, yeah, so…
Csaba: a little bit.
Aarsh Shah: Yeah, in Prysm, we were missing this branch, where when both get blobs and…
Aarsh Shah: So, if has blobs exist, you call has blobs.
Aarsh Shah: You push out the bitmap, you push out the request bitmap for the data columns, right?
Aarsh Shah: Then you call Get blobs V3.
Aarsh Shah: Ifs blobs doesn't exist. Then you call Get blobsv3, you update your request bitmap, and you push that out.
Aarsh Shah: But if both has blobs and GetBloves returns empty.
Aarsh Shah: because you have no blobs in your mempool. Even in that case, you need to push out a request bitmap of all ones, saying, I want
Aarsh Shah: All the data columns.
Aarsh Shah: And, I have nothing.
Aarsh Shah: So that edge case we were missing in Prysm.
Csaba: Okay.
Aarsh Shah: Does that answer your question?
Csaba: I think I got it, but yeah, I have to look into the details.
Kamil Salakhiev: Okay, yeah, thanks, Aarsh.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, let's proceed with EL updates. Yeah, Bosul, anything on Sparse blobside?
Bosul Mun: Hi.
Bosul Mun: On this past before.
Bosul Mun: I'm working… on the… Oh, no.
Bosul Mun: a partial Transaction size cap PR, so whatever PRs after first blob is merged in on Master.
Bosul Mun: And… Also, the problem that occurred from handover.
Bosul Mun: So I'm fixing some bugs related to sparse blob, and…
Bosul Mun: also working on the QUIC listener, integrating the QUIC listener on the gap. I'm working on prototype of that proposal.
Bosul Mun: Hmm… That's all from my side, but I guess Caba has more… More works.
Bosul Mun: Thank you.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, let's pass the mic to Caba.
Csaba: Yes, so… sparse blob pool, I have… A few modifications.
Csaba: also… touching Get blobs before, so…
Csaba: I hope those will land today.
Csaba: the…
Csaba: the… the specification is asking for… for sending… I mean, the PeerDAS specification is asking for… for 41 bitmaps, but, we are currently in the implementation. We are focusing on… on the…
Csaba: first…
Csaba: 63 cells… 64… first 64 cells, and that creates a few edge cases that we are fixing now with Bosul in the codebase. So, yeah, I…
Csaba: My guess is that today there will be updates, and so if you are testing against it, and testing PeerDAS before fall, just expect that there will be changes today.
Csaba: If Today, if you would custody columns in the upper part, you could bump into issues.
Csaba: So, yeah, anyway, fixes, I don't know.
Csaba: in branches. Blanches will be PRs soon, and then they will be merged.
Csaba: What was the question?
Csaba: I see a question popping up.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, question… are there gonna be any spec change, or there is already?
Csaba: So does…
Csaba: there are some discrepancies between the PeerDAS spec and the EIP implementation at the moment. So, I think…
Csaba: There will be spec qualifications, I think. But I think the…
Csaba: the direction I'm going with the implementation is more… is closer to the PeerDAS spec.
Csaba: What else? Yeah, that's for the… for the sparse blob pool.
Csaba: Then, other changes… Hmm… I have a new EIP called, Distributed Block Instruction, EIP 8C71.
Csaba: Which is… Basically, the old idea of using, those subnets and, and,
Csaba: And sell our messaging with bitmaps.
Csaba: We have the machinery for that now.
Csaba: defined, model is implemented, so this is… this is proposed for… for Hegota, so I hope by the time we will have… everyone will have the…
Csaba: Partial messaging, up to speed.
Csaba: And then we can… we can use these columns to… to do, distributed deconstruction, with the aim
Csaba: of reducing the CPU load.
Csaba: on… so it's double aim, one is reducing the CPU load on… simple aim. One is reducing the CPU load on super nodes. The second one is making the construction more robust.
Csaba: And faster. And the third one is providing a mode in which we can reconstruct even without super nodes.
Csaba: So, yeah, the EIP is targeting these three gains, basically, bringing in…
Csaba: a chunk of the, of the Fortas system.
Csaba: to the… to the definition. It's called RowDAS, let's see the discussions about it.
Csaba: Yeah, these are the updates that's come to my mind QUICly.
Kamil Salakhiev: Sounds good.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, maybe we can, I don't know, go deeper into this RowDAS EIP, some call.
Kamil Salakhiev: Anyways… I'm just thinking, like, you know, also in the lights of this…
Kamil Salakhiev: lean DA ideas, like, we have,
Kamil Salakhiev: I think rows are also committed via Merkle trees there, and there is, like, row root there, so, I don't know, like, well, just curious…
Kamil Salakhiev: It would be interesting to see, like, what might be…
Kamil Salakhiev: The commitment scheme there. Maybe at the first iteration, it's still kzg, but in future.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah.
Csaba: Yeah, let's leave the future for the future.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, yeah.
Csaba: Yeah, of course.
Kamil Salakhiev: kzzy.
Csaba: then we can iterate, we can… we can change that, we can… we can definitely use Medical. It has its cost disadvantage, but we might…
Csaba: Want to do it for… for being post-quantum.
Csaba: That's…
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah.
Csaba: We can…
Kamil Salakhiev: Everything… everything gets a bit more expensive.
Kamil Salakhiev: sometimes not a bit, but I presume a lot more expensive with PQ.
Csaba: Yeah, I think that ZK is… I mean, the aim is to keep that overhead low, but there will be overhead, there's no question.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah.
Kamil Salakhiev: Okay, nice, thanks. Yeah, FOCIL, anything you want to share about Nethermind updates?
Kamil Salakhiev: Oh, we cannot hear you if you're speaking.
Kamil Salakhiev: Still cannot hear you.
Kamil Salakhiev: Okay, yeah,
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, let's have only updating chat. Snap 2, Sparse on DevNet. Alright, nice.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, I'm just curious, in general, in the light of these,
Kamil Salakhiev: partial messages and partial pool updates. Does it make sense to start conversations around the next BPO efforts, or it's too early, maybe we should just…
Kamil Salakhiev: observe, like, the… Well, this partial post is not on the mainnet. I think for the partial messages.
Kamil Salakhiev: some nodes already on domain, if I'm not mistaken.
Kamil Salakhiev: But anyway… If anyone has any thoughts on that,
Kamil Salakhiev: Because I think the last BPO of fork was somewhere around January, if I'm not mistaken.
Kamil Salakhiev: And…
Kamil Salakhiev: Well, everyone is just so focused with Glamsterdam, and maybe that's not, the… reverse right now.
Kamil Salakhiev: Okay, yeah, maybe. Let's get back…
Kamil Salakhiev: a bit later for these conversations. Yeah, let's proceed with Waggle protocol. Yes, Sukun, do you wanna…
Kamil Salakhiev: We started?
Sukun Tarachandani: Sure, yeah.
Sukun Tarachandani: So…
Sukun Tarachandani: The issue is that, yeah, everyone who might have an opinion, I've already talked about the protocol with them.
Sukun Tarachandani: So, I'm not sure if this is new information for a new one, but sure, I will go through
Sukun Tarachandani: Thanks, QUICly. I am audible, right?
Daniel Knopik: Yep.
Sukun Tarachandani: Yeah, so the aim of the protocol, broadly, is that this is gossip sub B2,
Sukun Tarachandani: And, like, if you read the gossip-sub specs, the aim was that it should be a baseline protocol for PubSub, on which you can build your own nicer PubSub protocol, more fancier protocol. But the problem was that it either did not offer the correct primitives, like topic streams, or…
Sukun Tarachandani: as we saw partial messages, or it offered some primitives which were just not working, at least for Ethereum, like a message ID, which is very closely tied to the set of bytes and, like, the hash of it.
Sukun Tarachandani: like, the scene cache and everything, which makes things very difficult to override. And, so, we have started moving away from these sorts of limitations by partial messages and topic streams.
Sukun Tarachandani: And the idea is that, okay, at this point, yeah, basically we start with a clean slate and put
Sukun Tarachandani: Roughly have a protocol which is equivalent to partial messages and topic streams, but without the burden of…
Sukun Tarachandani: One backwards compatibility, and two…
Sukun Tarachandani: some of the other things which we felt went wrong with gossip-sub, so I'll just very QUICly go through them. Yeah, so one thing, just at the start, this is, like, very orthogonal to what your connection to the peer is. Like, it really does not matter if your connection is a QUIC connection, TCP connection, carrier pigeons, multi-stream select, edge 3 streams.
Sukun Tarachandani: Like, whatever you give, like, a broadcast protocol can work with any connection, right? Yeah.
Sukun Tarachandani: So, like, we can run this on lib P2P, and then when we get ETH P2P with a fancier protocol select, we can just move to those connections. Like, this protocol has nothing to do with
Sukun Tarachandani: The transport that the peer is talking to us on.
Sukun Tarachandani: So, some things that we want to, like, have in Waggle and, like, fix in Waggle, like, the details of the spec car and the specs link.
Sukun Tarachandani: please, like, engage there, and we will keep on, like, iterating. These are very… this is a very early spec, we'll keep on iterating, but yeah, that's the place for discussion.
Sukun Tarachandani: The other thing I'd like to also say is that we can move this spec discussion to data P2P if people want to, like, break away from lib P2P sort of thing. Yeah. So QUICly, basically, yeah, the idea is message semantics should be in the application, like, think of aggregates, I feel that's, like, the best example.
Sukun Tarachandani: Currently, there are 16 aggregators who send only 2 or 3 distinct aggregates among them. But for gossip sub, these are 16 distinct messages, and there is no easy way to hack the message ID function to make them as 2 or 3 distinct messages only.
Sukun Tarachandani: You will end up sending all the 16 distinct messages, because on the wire, they are distinct, as the selection proof of the aggregators is distinct.
Sukun Tarachandani: The other part is peer scoring. This is also something that application needs to control, because different applications have different requirements, and in general, application also wants to do a lot of cross-topic peer scoring, basically.
Sukun Tarachandani: So, like, yeah, it's roughly… this should be in the application. To the question that, are we losing out on the fact that if gossip-sub has this handcrafted application scoring logic over theirs.
Sukun Tarachandani: My opinion of it is that if that logic is so important, we should provide it as a library, not as a framework that you opt into. So it should be, like, a library that you can use if you want, otherwise, like, discard, but the ownership of the thing should be completely in the application.
Sukun Tarachandani: More contentious, consider removing a fixed mesh, and just forward to a random peerset.
Sukun Tarachandani: I do think we can make this work, like, this is what EC-broadcast also does, it has no fixed peer set, and peers just randomly push.
Sukun Tarachandani: The only problem is that you need to ensure that you have a sufficient set of peers, so that you are eventually picked by that peer's random broadcasting logic.
Sukun Tarachandani: Yeah, basically, yeah, the biggest reason why we are doing this, because, like, the performance, I expect, will be equivalent to this sort of thing, with topic streams plus partial messages that gossip gives us.
Sukun Tarachandani: But the biggest reason is that once we moved to Waggle, we would have dropped a lot of code. And, like, it would have simplified a lot of the codebase that we have currently.
Sukun Tarachandani: This does…
Sukun Tarachandani: make the upgrade path slightly difficult, but I don't think this change that we need to upgrade, which is tune the mesh size of gossip-sub, basically application needs to tell the gossip-sub that
Sukun Tarachandani: change your topic, attestation topics D value to 8, to 6, to 12, whatever it wants to. It is a small change for gossip-sub. I can't imagine why other people's change would be large on this specific thing.
Sukun Tarachandani: And yeah, of course, like, one of the reasons why we want this is that, yeah, basically.
Sukun Tarachandani: We have a… there are a bunch of places where we have a large message, where the chunks of the message are meaningful, and we can verify them independently, and we can…
Sukun Tarachandani: like, distribute them independently. We see this with attestations, where, strictly speaking, it's… they are all separate messages, but we can still combine them and look at it as a single message.
Sukun Tarachandani: Same way for data columns. In principle, you can run EC broadcast on top of this thing, and, like, yeah, so also get the benefits.
Sukun Tarachandani: And, like, yeah, the whole point is that if you think of a baseline broadcast protocol, there are only… there is only so much design space there. Like, if you say message semantics in the application, what you want is a way to make topic
Sukun Tarachandani: topic streams to the peer, and these streams should ideally be of two types. One is, like, the exact data that you're sending, and the other is control, which is, like, your state of that message, or your state of that slot that you're syncing with the peer.
Sukun Tarachandani: And I think we can get there, yeah. So, the specs are here…
Sukun Tarachandani: I will, yeah, now take questions. I hope that did not take too much time, because I think everyone has this context already.
Sukun Tarachandani: Yeah, shout us.
Aarsh Shah: I have a question. So, I discussed this with Casey…
Aarsh Shah: You know, when we met up internally, and…
Aarsh Shah: Why do we need topic streams at all? What does topic mean in this world? So, we are just designing a PubSub library that is specific for ETH. Now, all our PubSub semantics right now is either pushed to everyone.
Aarsh Shah: That you are connected to, like, blocks?
Aarsh Shah: Or it's request response.
Aarsh Shah: Like, data columns where, you know, we can use partial messages and have, like, these bitmaps.
Aarsh Shah: Are you in attestations?
Aarsh Shah: So, if it boils down to either send it to everyone, or send a request and get a response.
Aarsh Shah: In that world, why do you need this topic abstraction or per-topic stream? Because
Aarsh Shah: At the ENR layer, you already know which peers can offer which topics, right? You know which peers custody which data columns, their attnets, their syncnets.
Aarsh Shah: So, when I get an ENR record and I connect to that peer, I kind of already know
Aarsh Shah: what they're offering, what messages they'll be able to give me if I send them a request.
Aarsh Shah: In the request response world.
Aarsh Shah: So, can we, like, design this such that there is just one stream, one topic to rule them all? You still need to score
Aarsh Shah: per topic.
Sukun Tarachandani: So…
Aarsh Shah: Yeah, you get what I'm saying? Like, what is…
Sukun Tarachandani: I get your point, but the whole reason why you want different streams is that those messages have different priorities. So if I'm sending the… a block to the peer and a attestation to the same peer, I don't want them to be head offline blocked with each other, I want them to travel parallel so that the peer gets the attestation in parallel to the block.
Sukun Tarachandani: Does it make sense? Like, if…
kasey: Could you…
Sukun Tarachandani: Yeah.
kasey: inside of a single stream, I guess, how does the multi-stream, you know, semantics, enable that? And remember that we're talking about, like, in a QUIC model as well, right?
Sukun Tarachandani: Yeah, yeah, so in the… that's my point, basically, that… so you want to send a block to the same peer and the attestation to the same peer. You don't want the attestation to wait for the block to be transmitted completely. So, you basically send the attestation on a different stream, that's…
Sukun Tarachandani: sort of what QUIC streams offer you. So your attestation will reach the pier in parallel with the block.
kasey: I guess I don't know where,
kasey: I don't… does the application ever convey the relative priority of the streams?
Sukun Tarachandani: You can convey, but it's round robin, so it also works that way. Yeah, it works fine with that. But you can convey the priority that is actually in master in go-quic, and we'll start using it soon. Yeah, but you can convey.
Sukun Tarachandani: It's actually, yeah, so… so the rust-QUIC ecosystem is much nicer, they can convey it today, and they can get done with it. Yeah, unfortunately, QUIC Go and even the Go and QUIC did not have it yet, but now they have it, so we can do this.
kasey: Okay, yeah, that makes a lot more sense. Yeah, and I suppose that the, that the stream is, essentially just, an abstraction, you know, it's essentially a field on the, on the messages,
kasey: So, so, so there's not really any costs to it.
Sukun Tarachandani: Yeah, basically it's,
Sukun Tarachandani: It's entirely at the QUIC layer, so yeah, there's really no cost to it, in the sense, if you are sending on the same stream, your frames will still contain stream ID 3 or 4 or whatever. Now they will con… like, different frames will contain different stream IDs, so there would… there won't be a wire cost to it over the other things.
Sukun Tarachandani: Having said that, a separate design where you say, if you want a stream per message, that also makes sense, and we can consider it.
kasey: Yeah, I did think, you know, I wonder if there could be some benefit to,
kasey: Combining certain messages,
kasey: Yeah, maybe… I guess you'd have to look in detail at the sizes of all these messages,
kasey: But yeah, I think… I think I'm gonna have to go rethink that… that point, based on what you just said. I didn't realize there was any way to control prioritization, so that actually is pretty important.
Sukun Tarachandani: M…
Sukun Tarachandani: Yeah, yeah, I can share the QUICCo thing here, but yeah, now there is priorities in QUICCo, so we can do that. And the Rust ecosystem definitely has priorities.
Sukun Tarachandani: Caba?
Csaba: Yeah, so yeah.
Csaba: Yeah, I wanted to speak about the fixed mesh versus random forwarding a little bit.
Sukun Tarachandani: Oh, oh yeah, sure, go ahead.
Csaba: Yeah, so one of the…
Csaba: data-flow routing is working very well for some applications, like streaming. What you lose there, typically, is…
Csaba: So there's two things. One is… is the… SP scolding becomes…
Csaba: Much less tight, because you don't have the symmetric relations, and that's a usual… difficulty with…
Csaba: With random forwarding-based schemes.
Csaba: And, yeah, the other one is…
Csaba: I don't remember what was the other one, but, but, scrolling is, is definitely one, something which… which we should be prepared. If, if we go with the building, then we should be prepared to, to handle that, to zync that a little bit, because the…
Csaba: The mesh has… has this advantage, that you have these symmetric relations, you have,
Csaba: the… you are getting…
Csaba: a constant feed of information from the LLP, then it just… it's just the title loop.
Csaba: The other thing that we have, for example, in the Mun pool, is the… is the sequentiality that you are using… losing withding, typically.
Csaba: So that depends on the application, but for example, in the case of the mempool with the noses, it's something, that matters, and that's why we are not doing RANO for voting, but we are doing,
Csaba: Kind of, A systematic choice based on
Csaba: some little bit of the message, that being the… the original… Sendal, of the transaction. So…
Csaba: Yeah, just, if we go and evaluate those two, just keep in mind that there are these two things, which…
Csaba: Which would suffer if we don't have the fixed mesh.
Csaba: Otherwise, I'm a big fan of the wording.
Sukun Tarachandani: Yeah, cool, thanks. So…
Sukun Tarachandani: Yeah, this is something that will definitely depend on simulations, whether this is working for us or not. Like, it… in terms of implementation, it is just so simple and nice, so if we can make the circuit, it would be really great.
Kamil Salakhiev: Sukun… this thing should not live in libp2p at all, I mean, it just could be built on top, right? So there shouldn't…
Sukun Tarachandani: So, it will all… yeah, the API will certainly be… add peer
Sukun Tarachandani: PLIT, comma connection, whatever connection you give, whatever PRIT you give, and completely independent from the P2P.
Sukun Tarachandani: So you can give it a raw QUIC connection, you can give it a TCP connection, whatever connection, as long as you can open a stream on it, that's fine, yeah.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, nice. Maybe we should specify that in…
Sukun Tarachandani: Vesh?
Sukun Tarachandani: Yeah, that's why I mentioned the specs bit, that we can move the discussion to… Entire B2B.
Sukun Tarachandani: To FOCIL, yeah, my point is on… the fact is that HTTP3 has a RFC which says this is how stream priorities should be for HTTP3.
Sukun Tarachandani: What QUIC stacks do is they just expose that same API for QUIC streams as well. Let me find the RFC chat QUICly.
Sukun Tarachandani: But the priority is simply stream.setPriety.
Sukun Tarachandani: That's led by EIP, sorry.
Sukun Tarachandani: So… the thing is that there is no…
Sukun Tarachandani: Priority RFC for QUIC, so everyone, like, chooses their favorite API, sort of, and most people settle on the HTTP one, because it's at least somewhat standard.
Sukun Tarachandani: This one, yeah.
Sukun Tarachandani: That is it. So, but this is all…
Sukun Tarachandani: very heavily work in progress. Like, it would have been nice if Raul and other CLs were here. Like, I have talked… already talked to, like, Prysm and Lighthouse is definitely on board. They are the ones drafting it.
Sukun Tarachandani: So, yeah, I… I would like to understand what other CLs need here to be more convinced of this.
Daniel Knopik: Maybe they'll be here next time.
Sukun Tarachandani: I mean, okay, yeah, that is the…
Sukun Tarachandani: brute force method of individually calling them. We can try that.
Sukun Tarachandani: Yeah.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, I'm curious, like, what also the update path could be. I think Aarsh mentioned that we might
Kamil Salakhiev: Have, like, backwards compatibility somehow.
Kamil Salakhiev: But I don't really see, I mean, how… Some people…
Sukun Tarachandani: Just if they are.
Kamil Salakhiev: only support Waggle, they might…
Kamil Salakhiev: I mean, do they… I mean, do they, like, have both… do they use both gossip Sub and…
Kamil Salakhiev: this Waggle at the same time for some period of time, or how it's gonna look?
Sukun Tarachandani: Yeah, so the plan is that, basically, via the ENR, we know whether the peer supports Waggle or not.
Sukun Tarachandani: If they support Waggle, you talk to them on Waggle. If they… yeah, if they don't support Waggle and you support Waggle, you talk to them on gossip sub. The problem with this plan in, like, this fashion is that you will end up increasing your bandwidth usage, because now you have
Sukun Tarachandani: a set of Waggle users and a set of gossip sub users, both using, like, if we set the same forward multipliers, a D of 8, basically, right? So you've sort of doubled your networking requirement for that topic. So it would be nice if we can somehow just reduce the gossip sub topic mesh size.
Sukun Tarachandani: like, yeah, pass this information to gossip-sub that, okay, I have a few Waggle peers, so I would prefer having fewer gossip-sub peers.
Kamil Salakhiev: Hmm.
Sukun Tarachandani: This one…
Csaba: SC.
Sukun Tarachandani: I hear.
Csaba: Yeah, that sounds messy, because it also interacts with peace calling and all kind of…
Csaba: You know, the cyclical.
Csaba: syncs, what's with the RPCs, which still go with the… with the higher degree.
Csaba: Because they don't support this, or do we make them contribute less? So…
Csaba: Yeah, that won't be an easy ride.
Sukun Tarachandani: I didn't see, I mean…
Sukun Tarachandani: I'm not sure if we can do anything else here, is the thing. Like, this is also what partial messages does, by the way. Like, it's still…
Csaba: I see…
Sukun Tarachandani: it under gossip sub, but it is exactly what partial messages is doing currently.
Csaba: Yeah, but this is a bigger change. For real, I think we need… a good…
Csaba: Implementation first from someone, then lots of testing.
Csaba: On… with that single implementation, and ironing out everything, and then basically switch over the other one.
Sukun Tarachandani: Hmm… okay.
Kamil Salakhiev: So… so more like a hard fork.
Kamil Salakhiev: Is that what you say?
Csaba: Yeah, more like I thought, but also before that we need… we need one implementation to be,
Csaba: High quality and tested in lots of distributed settings.
Csaba: Nothing about interoperability, just the actual protocol design.
Csaba: Gives the performance advantages, and… Has no,
Csaba: Shortcomings, or backsides, or whatever.
Csaba: Yeah, I think we should go that way.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, Sir Casey?
kasey: I had kind of, like, a question about QUIC, So, when you're…
kasey: tweaking priority, you're messing with, is it, like, max data? And I was just wondering, I assume if the sender is ignoring that.
kasey: Ignoring your flow control signals, I guess.
kasey: we'll go QUIC, just terminate them, or,
kasey: is there enough, information bubbling up to go to the BTP to integrate that into peer scoring?
Sukun Tarachandani: I'm sorry, I missed that question. Can you repeat?
kasey: Yeah, just, like, thinking more about the premise of, like, using, QUIC to manage, like, head of line blocking and prioritization,
kasey: I'm just wondering, if you have, like, a misbehaving peer, does libptp have access to the information about how the peer is, ignoring the prioritization signals so that it can downscore them?
Sukun Tarachandani: Good question.
Sukun Tarachandani: I will have to check.
kasey: Because I'm guessing go-quic probably just, like, terminates the connection or something, you know, and then they, like…
kasey: Connect again. And then it's, like, outside the scope of…
kasey: or the view of, Lib ETP, you know?
Sukun Tarachandani: I think so, yeah, possibly.
kasey: Okay.
Sukun Tarachandani: That's it, like… In terms… you can only control priorities on the send side, basically.
Sukun Tarachandani: Yeah, what a peer does, basically, you generally can't control on the priorities then.
Sukun Tarachandani: Because you want to send two pieces to the peer, and you don't want one to wait for the other, which, like, has a higher priority than the other, say.
Sukun Tarachandani: So… Basically, on the send side, you control whether message A has a higher priority or message B.
Sukun Tarachandani: we can… We do… we can inform the peer of our priority, and if they don't… Prioritize.
Sukun Tarachandani: Maybe we can detect it, but yeah, I'm not sure if the details of go-quic offers this API.
kasey: Okay, yeah, we can follow up.
Sukun Tarachandani: Yep.
Sukun Tarachandani: Oh, yeah, good point on the score.
Kamil Salakhiev: Okay, nice. Yeah, I think we definitely need to discuss more about that.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, maybe we can… yeah, I can QUICly touch on some updates on… Why is that, Aarsh?
Kamil Salakhiev: I can put a touch.
Aarsh Shah: Bye, Ben.
Kamil Salakhiev: I guess it's just recognition of the, whatever. Some feature, yeah.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, we can QUICly touch on, blobs and blobs. Yeah, just had some new input, maybe, I don't know, people would be curious to…
Kamil Salakhiev: Learning about, like, Yeah.
Kamil Salakhiev: So basically…
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, the initial idea was that… yeah, I kind of presented this on ACDC, I'm not gonna repeat it too much, but…
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, basically, we could, like, kind of, like, reuse the existing column subnet topics to, also distribute
Kamil Salakhiev: execution payloads, and we can kind of use partial messages for that, so that appears only, like, signal that…
Kamil Salakhiev: For some topics, they're only interested in the first, like, n rows that correspond to execution payloads.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, kind of… There was a feedback that, yeah, we might actually need to split
Kamil Salakhiev: these two, kind of, topics, I mean, not to…
Kamil Salakhiev: Have, not to reuse column subnets for execution payloads, but rather introduce a new set of topics.
Kamil Salakhiev: And there also was some… some new input. I guess it's kinda… if we do that, what we can is, yeah, we can optimize, actually, some stuff, because, like, for column subnets, today we use KZG.
Kamil Salakhiev: And we use that for multiple reasons, so we can, like.
Kamil Salakhiev: check not only that an individual cell corresponds to KZG
Kamil Salakhiev: Commitment, but also, like, we're ensuring that
Kamil Salakhiev: Basically, a recording was done correctly, all the properties.
Kamil Salakhiev: And if we think more about that, we actually don't need that for…
Kamil Salakhiev: execution payload, because if we do that, I mean, builder would need to, once it encodes the data into subnet… well, into columns, then extends them, basically wasting some time for, calculation of all of these
Kamil Salakhiev: KZG proofs, and… Yeah, that's kinda like…
Kamil Salakhiev: I don't know, around 100 milliseconds or more.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, what we can do, and it's actually… Very aligned with several staff.
Kamil Salakhiev: Is instead just do… Merkle root commitments, and…
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, basically, like, for each column, we have column root, and then for each route, we also, like, put them into some global payload route, and this payload route can go into
Kamil Salakhiev: Payload beat, and…
Kamil Salakhiev: And then the message, the payload partial data column sidecar, would look like, basically very similar to
Kamil Salakhiev: data column sidecars, but we don't use kzg proofs, but we use Kennedy's Merkel proofs. So, yeah.
Kamil Salakhiev: And…
Kamil Salakhiev: this kind of makes sense from multiple perspectives. I mean, yeah, first it's cheaper. I mean, builder would not need to kind of spend so much time for this KZG proofs calculation.
Kamil Salakhiev: And also… If you're paying attention, there was recently a proposal about Lindia.
Kamil Salakhiev: And, basically the idea there is…
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, we're replacing kzg commitments because they're not post-quantum secure.
Kamil Salakhiev: We've… Merkle root commitments.
Kamil Salakhiev: plus… There will be a snark.
Kamil Salakhiev: Which is LeanVM proof.
Kamil Salakhiev: And the… Yeah, I spoke with authors of this… Eth research post, basically.
Kamil Salakhiev: So, the message actually is gonna be.
Kamil Salakhiev: Well, what would go into the sidecar message, in that case for Lyndia?
Kamil Salakhiev: is actually exactly what I described here, because, like, yeah, we're doing this…
Kamil Salakhiev: We're doing, actually, two things here. We're doing… Column?
Kamil Salakhiev: commitment via Merkle, and also raw commitment. But the raw commitment is only needed for snarks, and, kind of for ensuring that, well, basically, error recording was done correctly.
Kamil Salakhiev: We don and yeah, for data columns, we will… only include, basically, this Merko Proof.
Kamil Salakhiev: Instead of KZG proof today.
Kamil Salakhiev: Because, like, if we… Yeah, if our Validator has the… The snark?
Kamil Salakhiev: If it has the… this global route, And then it has the…
Kamil Salakhiev: Merko tree, path, basically this Merko proof.
Kamil Salakhiev: Then it can prove that, well, individual cell was
Kamil Salakhiev: Properly, well, committed and verified this cell.
Kamil Salakhiev: So what I'm saying is basically.
Kamil Salakhiev: If we go into… if we actually use for…
Kamil Salakhiev: if we actually use payload commitment, well, this Merkle commitment, for payloads today.
Kamil Salakhiev: It's gonna be a very easy path for us in future when we switch to Lindia.
Kamil Salakhiev: And,
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, and it also brings, like, other advantages, which I mentioned, like, no, these expensive KZG proofs calculations.
Kamil Salakhiev: This actually could be a good foundation for in future work, because, like, this is actually how, column subnets for data is gonna look like. So, yeah, it's kind of… so when we have mandatory proofs and we only, like, need to custody
Kamil Salakhiev: But we don't need, like, the full execution payload, well, we don't need to subscribe to all execution payload column subnets anymore.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, basically, data columns, they will use exactly the same mechanism.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, what I'm saying here is, like, yeah, we can… yeah, because, like, people… there is a question, like, why not just use a z broadcast here?
Kamil Salakhiev: And it might be a good fit here, but…
Kamil Salakhiev: We… if we use, like.
Kamil Salakhiev: if you broadcast, like, some arrests, whatever, like.
Kamil Salakhiev: Instead of this columns mechanism. Yeah, we will introduce it, but we will replace it once we have mandatory proofs and ZK EVMs.
Kamil Salakhiev: And, yeah.
Kamil Salakhiev: kind of, like, reading a bit more of what's going on in Lindia land and, like,
Kamil Salakhiev: Hmm, yeah, where are we going?
Kamil Salakhiev: From my perspective, it kind of makes sense the most, to be honest.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, basically, that's all I had. Yeah, if…
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, I will update the EIP.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, maybe gather some more feedback.
Kamil Salakhiev: With that idea, not yet, anyway.
Kamil Salakhiev: Just wanted to share.
Kamil Salakhiev: some update on that, so ERC people have some thoughts.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, Daniel?
Daniel Knopik: So, if I understood you correctly, you do not want to erasure encode the… Payload.
Kamil Salakhiev: We do it… yeah, we do it… we basically do the same as we do for blobs today. We basically represent our…
Kamil Salakhiev: Payload in blobs, then we extend it.
Kamil Salakhiev: And then, yeah, we do this multiple tree commitment instead of KZG.
Daniel Knopik: Alright,
Daniel Knopik: Okay.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, sorry, I missed it. There are other questions.
Kamil Salakhiev: 3 is not proving our rust extensions correct. Yeah, it's… it is not proving our rust extension's correctness.
Kamil Salakhiev: But I think we don't need this, because…
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, we cannot, when we receive individual columns, we cannot ensure that, basically, error coding was done correctly, and these column cells, they actually correspond to properly extended blobs.
Kamil Salakhiev: Not blobs, but payloads, in that case. But we don't need this, because, if, eventually this…
Kamil Salakhiev: Column data is garbage.
Kamil Salakhiev: then…
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, PTC members, they will not be able to reconstruct, and then they will not basically commit that, well, they, they absorb the payload, it is valid.
Kamil Salakhiev: So…
Kamil Salakhiev: you know, we don't need that in my… I think, like, we… which is why… because we have… exactly because, like, we have this PTC members protection.
Csaba: Yeah, so for the full payload, I don't think we need it.
Csaba: But… If we do this…
Csaba: with the argument that then we will need it for sampling. For the sampling, we will need that correctness. No, for sampling…
Kamil Salakhiev: Sampling will… will not… yeah.
Kamil Salakhiev: For some reason.
Csaba: So that…
Kamil Salakhiev: Yes, something will be needed when we have mandatory proofs.
Csaba: Thank you.
Kamil Salakhiev: EVMs, and basically, yeah, and we need to kind of… we'll be putting this, execution payload into custody columns.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, then we need sampling, and the sampling and recording coding will be proved via snark.
Kamil Salakhiev: So, we're not bothering with that much now, but…
Kamil Salakhiev: The interesting thing is that if we do this Merkle commitment.
Kamil Salakhiev: then the message will look exactly, actually, how it's gonna look like in Lindia.
Kamil Salakhiev: Already. And then, yeah, future transition will be super easy.
Kamil Salakhiev: Interesting.
Kamil Salakhiev: Daniel, I see your hand, saw your hand.
Daniel Knopik: Yeah, yeah, never mind.
Kamil Salakhiev: Okay.
Kamil Salakhiev: Merkle for those two. Yeah, in Lindia, we do Merkle 3…
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, with Merkle on top of Rose as well.
Kamil Salakhiev: But this is only needed for the snark. I mean, I don't want to, like, misinterpret
Kamil Salakhiev: like, what… how Lindia works?
Kamil Salakhiev: but yeah, I spoke to…
Kamil Salakhiev: towel and long, and they said, like, yeah, basically for…
Kamil Salakhiev: the commit… I mean, for the proof that goes into this column sidecar message, yeah, we only need the Merkle proof that goes via this, column
Kamil Salakhiev: I would say, like, via this proof that goes to… proofs for columns, yeah, we don't need, like, the proof for rows in the… in this proof. I mean, in the data column.
Kamil Salakhiev: So, I'll spacing a little bit.
Kamil Salakhiev: It's because… Yes, for s…
Kamil Salakhiev: For cell-level splitting? Actually, yeah, speaking of that, yeah, with this approach, with Merkle commitment, we can also do
Kamil Salakhiev: Partial messages.
Kamil Salakhiev: Because, like, one option could be just, yeah, we signed the whole column.
Kamil Salakhiev: But yeah, we cannot then… we cannot, if we receive just individual cells, yeah, we cannot ensure that they are valid.
Csaba: So…
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah.
Csaba: Yeah, my understanding is that one of the underlying assumptions is that you basically prove the correspondence between the
Csaba: the different Merkle.
Csaba: proofs via ZKPs.
Csaba: And that's… that's why you can do things, but that's not cheap. So… so you don't have the…
Csaba: the symmetry and the homomorphism of the KZG.
Csaba: you are using Merkle sleeves, but then you don't have the homologue properties. You have different things on those and columns, and you have to prove, a few things. For example, the correspondence of the two, you have to prove
Csaba: Yeah, and just… a few things needs ZKPs there, and let's see how the costs play out.
Csaba: I think it's… it's… a bit more expensive than just playing with KZG, so we will.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, well, it is expensive.
Csaba: We want to tell, and we have to play it out, basically, what are the prices and what other adoptions exist.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, well… well, the good thing is, like, we only need a single snark proof plus this global route that goes into BID eventually. This is some…
Kamil Salakhiev: Bright future. But the bad thing is this LeanVM proof is, like, between 128 to 512 kilobytes, depending on the exact scheme that…
Kamil Salakhiev: will be used. And that…
Csaba: They're just dead…
Kamil Salakhiev: Much more than… acted.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah.
Csaba: If it's operating on a large amount of data, it's… it's proportionally expensive.
Kamil Salakhiev: Dude, exactly. Yeah, yeah.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, there's also, like, this thing called… yeah, they're measuring in the post also, like, the performance, like, how much
Kamil Salakhiev: how long it basically takes to come up with the snark for different sizes of data, depending on different parameters.
Kamil Salakhiev: But yeah.
Kamil Salakhiev: Anyways…
Csaba: That's also not cheap is kzg, so we are choosing between expensive and very expensive.
Csaba: compared to that, the… yeah, so we have a few, I think, a few options on the table.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah,
Csaba: I think we have to, kind of, Map it out nicely.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, main point is being, like, we…
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, we kind of need this segmentation for the payload.
Kamil Salakhiev: In my opinion.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, we kind of need to come up with the exact scheme. I mean, yeah, this is still, like, some proposals, ideas, so yeah, definitely, like, the opinion of client scheme and everyone else kind of matters.
Kamil Salakhiev: I'm not saying, like, we don't need EC-broadcast, I'm just saying that if we introduce, for example, EC-broadcast for payload.
Kamil Salakhiev: It will be then replaced by the
Kamil Salakhiev: kind of similar mechanism, because the payload will eventually go into column subnets. But AC broadcast still kind of need it for things like, I don't know, maybe linear proofs propagation, or…
Kamil Salakhiev: Some other heavy data.
Kamil Salakhiev: That, yeah, that is not basically… cannot be put into this column structure.
Csaba: Yeah, I think one of the…
Csaba: One of the questions is how much Teams are eager to… To do segmentation, and…
Csaba: And get the benefits of not doing the stolen folder that we are doing now.
Csaba: Because… I think it kind of was so…
Csaba: Decides how much… how much you push on this?
Csaba: I think it would be really good to…
Csaba: To find a way, a glean a way to do the segmentation, at least.
Csaba: As soon as possible, and…
Csaba: The closest fork we can, because we are suffering from the delay of the… of the large message diffusion in… in different parts of the… of the system.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah. I was asking about, like.
Kamil Salakhiev: General segmentation for any kind of message or for the payload.
Csaba: But the…
Csaba: the big one that we have at the moment is a payload, so… so I think that's the, like…
Csaba: That's what we should address. But we are also introducing new ones, obviously.
Csaba: But I think it's the payload where we know that we would gain a lot from segmentation, and there are different ways of achieving it.
Csaba: And basically, just the question is how much teams would be eager to jump on a scheme that we…
Csaba: device, to get… lower delays.
Kamil Salakhiev: Right.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, just speaking of, like, how much effort would be required implementing that, there is no EL changes, which is a good thing.
Kamil Salakhiev: This whole thing could be done on CL, purely.
Kamil Salakhiev: Because, yeah, we're basically changing the bit structure, we… Introducing new topics.
Kamil Salakhiev: And other than that, yeah, basically, yeah, getting the execution table from EL and just segmenting it into columns, and then propagate.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, sukun will be talking about the second.
Kamil Salakhiev: to compute the proofs described in India, right? Oh, I need to check in our school. Yeah, there is… it's research post, if someone could QUICly find it.
Csaba: Mostly hardware which was used in that post is something like 16 or 32 cores.
Csaba: machine, so… and there's a large amount of lamp, so I think we should carefully look into those numbers.
kasey: Yeah, when I've looked at some of these, like, Poseidon-type schemes in the past, it's, like, yeah, very, very CPU-intensive, takes…
kasey: takes a lot of time. So, if it's something that's happening, you know, on the slot.
kasey: network deadline, that… but I guess we don't really need to actually do those proofs, kind of to Caba's original point, in order to use it for, distribution, just for, DA, and we don't need to do DA on the execution payload, because we can prove it.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, we don't need now.
Kamil Salakhiev: But eventually, Yeah, we might.
Kamil Salakhiev: Searching for another day.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yes.
Csaba: Yeah, but that is definitely a question about, how this…
Csaba: Interests with self-building in the future, if you would have to do that for the blog that you build.
kasey: Yeah, the premise is that, like, an advantage of this is that it's gonna slip right into this future scheme, and… but then the future scheme is, like.
kasey: You know, questionable in its,
kasey: Practicality, in terms of time, then… then it might be worth…
kasey: Making sure we have the right projection for how that gets optimized.
Kamil Salakhiev: Hmm.
Kamil Salakhiev: Right.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, one concern could be, I mean, if the execution payload goes into good data columns, and they are committed via this snark proof.
Kamil Salakhiev: Then the builder, yeah, kind of has this delay.
Kamil Salakhiev: Which is bad, but… I don't know, maybe there will be some more discussion throughout that future.
kasey: Yeah, I feel it.
Kamil Salakhiev: I mean, just doing the.
Csaba: That's true, that'll be.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, yeah. Maybe they can just, yeah, commit via Merkle in the beginning, and then…
Kamil Salakhiev: create… I mean, and then start propagating the beat, whatever, and… after…
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, just, and the snark goes after that.
Kamil Salakhiev: I don't know.
Csaba: I'm looking into the direction of mixed schemes, where you are not… doing the… The post-continue.
Csaba: resistant part for the… for the Lloyd short time stem distribution, and you're kind of delaying
Csaba: The part where you need.
Csaba: the Beaconis.
Csaba: On a different timeline, but…
Csaba: Not sure how that works, just it's… Yeah, definitely. It's a general technique, to use cheaper encryption from FLM keys for short-term things, and then put another envelope on top, basically.
Csaba: For the longer term.
Csaba: So that's the direction I'm trying to explore.
Kamil Salakhiev: Nice. Yeah, I think we need to kind of consolidate our efforts, because, there will also be this EIP about, Lindia,
Kamil Salakhiev: sometime… at some point of time. Yeah, also, like, just ensure that…
Kamil Salakhiev: You already wrote us, Caba, also.
Kamil Salakhiev: Aligned with all of that.
Csaba: Yep.
Kamil Salakhiev: Yeah, just kind of, like, putting everything together. Makes sense.
Kamil Salakhiev: Alright, I think that's all we have.
Kamil Salakhiev: For today, unless there are any other questions or topics?
Kamil Salakhiev: If not, yeah, then thanks everyone for joining. See you in two weeks.
Daniel Knopik: A…
Kamil Salakhiev: Bye.